# lason D. Rodis

Software Engineer jasrodis.tk

#### **Profile**

An ambitious and dynamic software engineer with background in research and over four years of experience who works to high personal standards. Self-motivated and confident working, either on own initiative or as an integral team member.

## **Work Experience**

2016-Present	Software Engineering Fellow CERN, <u>cern.ch</u> Beams Department, Beam Instrumentation, Software Section
2015-2016	Software Engineer, CERN, cern.ch Beams Department, Beam Instrumentation, Software Section
2014-2015	Research Associate / Software Engineer, Scan Group, <u>scan.di.uoa.gr</u> Department of Informatics & Telecommunications, University of Athens.
2011-2015	Freelance web developer and administrator.
2011-2012	<b>Tech support,</b> Hellenic Telecommunications Organisation S.A, <u>ote.gr</u>

## **Education & Training**

Coursera	Machine Learning - Stanford, Introduction to Particle Physics - UniGE, Nanotechnology Basics - RICE, VC with Git - Atlassian, Algorithms - Princeton
2015-2018	Efficient Scientific Computing INFN, SCRUM training, CERN Accelerator School, Communication Training, FESA Hands-on Training, Introduction to MEAN.js, CERN, Security training
2009-2016	BSc Department of Informatics & Telecommunications, University of Athens, 240 ECTS
2009	Graduated from "Lycée Léonin", Greek-French High school.

## **Projects & Services**

## CERN Beam Instrumentation Software Portal

Web application used for delivering and launching ExpertGuis and documenting FESA Classes Based on JHipster: Maven, MySQL, Spring Boot, AngularJS, WebSockets, ElasticSearch, Docker.

## **LHC Feedback Dashboard**

An expert monitoring suite for the LHC beam-based feedbacks. Based on FESA C++, Maven, JavaFX

#### **Dataviewer**

Data visualisation library, github link.

Based on Maven, JavaFX, Jetty, WebSockets, plotly.js

## Scan Group Flspace, fispace.eu, bitbucket.org/fispace

FIspace is an open-source social network platform for B2B collaboration.

**Web Application** - Junior Full stack developer. Based on Maven, Spring MVC, Atmosphere Framework, jQuery, AngularJS, Bower, Grunt and Keycloak.

**Diploma Thesis** based on **Univerself**, <u>univerself-project.eu</u>

**Thesis Title:** Adapting Policy-based Management of Future Networks using Collaborative Filtering Techniques.

Based on Java Swing, Web services REST, owl, rdf, MySQL.

Bentley Motors EQtoolHelper

Data analysis software package of the "NAIM for Bentley" audio amplifier.

Based on Java SE, Swing, JAXB.

Freelance Various websites developed with CMS platforms, JHipster stack

## **IT Skills & Expertise**

Languages Java, C/C++, Javascript
Java EE, Spring, Swing/FX
Web Angular, jQuery, JHipster
Databases SQL, NoSQL, TimeSeries

Dev/Ops Maven/Gradle, gitlab-ci, Docker

Various CMS, git, Agile/Scrum, Bash, Cubase/Ableton Live

OS Linux, OS X, Windows

## **Volunteering**

TEDxCERN, Official CERN Guide

### Languages

Greek Native English C2 French C2

#### **Interests**

Learning, Teaching, Snowboarding, Camping, Sailing, Hiking, Travelling, Music, Trading

## **Publications & Conferences**

- [3] lason Rodis, Athanasios Topaloudis, 'Common Standards for JavaFX GUI Development and its application to the Renovation of the CERN Beam Instrumentation Software Portal and Delivery Mechanism', for the 16th International Conference on Accelerator and Large Experimental Physics Control Systems, ICALEPCS 2017
- [2] Diogo Alves, **Iason Rodis**, Stephen Jackson, 'A monitoring system for the beam-based feed-backs in the LHC', for the Real Time Conference (RT), 2016 IEEE-NPSS.
- [1] R. Arapoglou, I. Rodis, P. Magdalinos, N. Alonistioti, 'Adapting Policy-based Management of Future Networks using Collaborative Filtering Techniques', for the 19th IEEE International Workshop on Computer Aided Modelling and Design of Communication Links and Networks.